Guide to the Sinclair Lewis Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1905-1963; Series I; 18.35 linear feet (45 boxes)
  - WRITINGS OF SINCLAIR LEWIS
    - Shorter Works
      - "Wrecks of Romance", undated (Box 42, Folder 407-409)
      - "You Seem to Forget," short story, undated (Box 42, Folder 410)
      - "Young Man Axelbrod", 1917 June (Box 42, Folder 411)
      - "Young Man, Go East", undated (Box 42, Folder 412)
      - "Youth," short story, 1930 February (Box 42, Folder 413)
      - Unidentified, 1932 January 9 (Box 42, Folder 414)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Feikema, Feike
      - "In Memoriam Address", 1951 January 28 (Box 43, Folder 415)
    - Freehof, Solomon
      - "It Can't Happen Here by Sinclair Lewis," speech, 1935 December 8 (Box 43, Folder 416)
    - Hughes, Langston
      - "Peace Conference in an American Town", undated (Box 43, Folder 417)
    - Levin, Jack
      - "Good Neighbor," playscripts, undated (Box 43, Folder 418-420)
    - Light, Martin
      - "H.G. Wells and Sinclair Lewis", 1962 (Box 43, Folder 421)
    - Maule, Harry E.
      - The Man From Main Street, galley proof, undated (Box 43, Folder 422-423)
    - Nathan, George Jean
      - "Art of the Night", undated (Box 43, Folder 424)
    - Shorer, Mark
      - Sinclair Lewis: An American Life, draft, 1963 January 28 (Box 44, Folder 425-429)
      - Sinclair Lewis: An American Life, draft, 1963 January 28 (Box 45, Folder 430-433)
    - Smith, Harrison
      - "From Main Street to Stockholm: Letters of Sinclair Lewis", undated (Box 45, Folder 434)
    - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster
      - "Sinclair Lewis, a Few Reminiscences," speech, 1952 February 1
    - Watkins, Ann
      - "Literature for Sale", 1941 November (Box 45, Folder 435)
    - Womer, M. Wayne
      - "Sinclair Lewis was My Sailor," essay, undated (Box 45, Folder 436)
    - Wooler, D.W.
      - "A Bibliography of the Translation of Sinclair Lewis' Novels", 1949 (Box 45, Folder 437)
- Correspondence, 1866-1964; Series II; 2.92 linear feet (7 boxes)
  Series II, Correspondence, housed in boxes 46-52, is organized into three subseries: Incoming Correspondence, Outgoing Correspondence, and Third Party Correspondence. Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence is first arranged alphabetically by correspondent or recipient and then chronologically within files. Third Party Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  The Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence subseries feature single letters or small groups with American and English writers and literary scholars and critics of the late nineteenth to mid twentieth century. Noteworthy correspondents include Sherwood Anderson, Stephen Vincent Benét, Bernard Berenson, Willa Cather, F. Scott Fitzgerald, Ernest Heminway, William Dean Howells, Jack London, Compton Mackenzie, Thomas Mann, Somerset Maugham, H. L. Mencken, Upton Sinclair, Chauncey Brewster Tinker, Rebecca West, Edith Wharton, and Thornton Wilder, among others. The subseries include correspondence with family, friends, publishers, and organizations.
  There are larger files of incoming and outgoing correspondence with Lewis's father, Edwin J. Lewis, dating from 1903 to 1926, and with his literary agent, Ann Watkins, dating from 1928 to 1948. Correspondence in the two subseries dates from 1902 to 1949.
  Third Party Correspondence, which dates from 1866 to 1964, consists of all loose third party correspondence in the collection. The bulk of these letters probably came into Lewis's possession as enclosures and, over time, were separated from the original letters.
  - INCOMING CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" General, 1916-1947 (Box 46, Folder 437a)
    - Aaron, Daniel, 1948 September 21 (Box 46, Folder 438)
    - Adams, George Matthew, 1915 September 26 (Box 46, Folder 439)
    - Adams, Samuel Hopkins, 1920 January 23 (Box 46, Folder 440)
    - America First Committee, 1941 May 17 (Box 46, Folder 441)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1942 April 10 (Box 46, Folder 442)
    - American Friends of Greece, 1941 May 8 (Box 46, Folder 443)
    - Anderson, Sherwood, 1920 December 1 (Box 46, Folder 444)
    - Angell, Norman, Sir, 1918 August 14 (Box 46, Folder 445)
    - Atherton, Gertrude Franklin Horn, 1938 (Box 46, Folder 446)
    - Austin, Mary Hunter, 1920, undated (Box 46, Folder 447)
    - Authors' Guild (U.S.), 1948 May 10 (Box 46, Folder 448)
    - "B" General, 1915-1947 (Box 46, Folder 449)
    - Benét, James Walker, 1914 March 3 (Box 46, Folder 450)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1910, 1912 (Box 46, Folder 451)
    - Berdan, John Milton, 1914-1917 (Box 46, Folder 452)
    - Berenson, Bernard, 1949 (Box 46, Folder 453)
    - Beresford, J. D. (John Davys), 1915-1922 (Box 46, Folder 454)
    - Bierstadt, Edward Hale, [1914?] (Box 46, Folder 455)
    - Bingham, Stillman H., 1915 (Box 46, Folder 456)
    - Birkhead, L. M. (Leon Milton), 1927-1946 (Box 46, Folder 457)
      Includes printed materials
    - Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1917, 1917-1920 (Box 46, Folder 458)
    - Boyce, Neith, undated (Box 46, Folder 459)
    - Brisbane, Arthur, 1934 October 13 (Box 46, Folder 460)
    - British War Relief Society (U.S.), 1941 May 14 (Box 46, Folder 461)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1944 April 23 (Box 46, Folder 462)
    - Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1938 November 16 (Box 46, Folder 463)
    - "C" General, 1907-1947 (Box 46, Folder 464)
      Includes photograph of Wells Lewis
    - Cabell, James Branch, 1917-1935 (Box 46, Folder 465)
    - Caldwell, Erskine, 1940 July 26 (Box 46, Folder 466)
    - Camp, W. H. (Wendell Holmes), undated (Box 46, Folder 467)
    - Carlisle, Helen Grace, 1942 April 2 (Box 46, Folder 468)
    - Carroll, Gladys Hasty, 1944 April 21 (Box 46, Folder 469)
    - Cather, Willa, 1922-1938 (Box 46, Folder 470)
    - Chidester, Ann, 1945-1946 (Box 46, Folder 471)
    - Cohen, Octavus Roy, 1921 February 18 (Box 46, Folder 472)
    - Comfort, Will Levington, [1915?] January 10 (Box 46, Folder 473)
    - Contemporary Jewish Record, 1942 February (Box 46, Folder 474)
    - Council Against Intolerance in America, 1948 February 11 (Box 46, Folder 475)
    - Cross, Wilbur L. (Wilbur Lucius), 1938 February 10 (Box 46, Folder 476)
    - Curtiss, Glenn Hammond, 1912 August 15 (Box 46, Folder 477)
    - "D" General, 1914-1947 (Box 46, Folder 478)
    - Darrow, Clarence, undated (Box 46, Folder 479)
    - Davis, Kenneth S. (Kenneth Sydney), 1943 August 17 (Box 46, Folder 480)
    - Dell, Floyd, 1917, [1920?] (Box 46, Folder 481)
    - Derleth, August William, [1937-1940] (Box 46, Folder 482)
    - Dimnet, Ernest, 1938 January 4 (Box 46, Folder 483)
    - Doubleday, Doran & Company, 1932-1933 (Box 46, Folder 484)
    - Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937, 1921 (Box 46, Folder 485)
    - "E" General, 1915-1947 (Box 46, Folder 486)
    - East and West Association, 1942 February 13 (Box 46, Folder 487)
    - Engle, Paul, 1944-1945 (Box 46, Folder 488)
    - Ernst, Cane & Berner, 1948 (Box 46, Folder 489)
      Includes carbons of letters from Lewis
    - "F" General, 1915-1947 (Box 46, Folder 490)
    - Fast, Howard, 1947 April 12 (Box 46, Folder 491)
    - Ferber, Edna, [1914?] March 29 (Box 46, Folder 492)
    - Fineman, Irving, undated (Box 46, Folder 493)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), [1921] January 26 (Box 46, Folder 494)
    - Flanagan, Hallie, 1937 March 17 (Box 46, Folder 495)
    - Flandrau, Charles Macomb, 1920 October 21 (Box 46, Folder 496)
    - Fletcher, Jefferson B., 1922 January 31 (Box 46, Folder 497)
    - Ford, Ford Maddox, 1938 November 25 (Box 46, Folder 498)
    - Ford, Harriet, 1921 (Box 46, Folder 499)
    - Frank, Waldo David, 1921 April 20 (Box 46, Folder 500)
    - Freedom House, 1942 March (Box 46, Folder 501)
    - "G" General, 1915-1947 (Box 47, Folder 502)
    - Gale, Zona, 1921-1922 (Box 47, Folder 503)
    - Galsworthy, John, 1920-1922 (Box 47, Folder 504)
    - Garland, Hamlin, undated (Box 47, Folder 505)
    - Gellhorn, Martha, 1941 November 25 (Box 47, Folder 506)
    - George, William, 1921-1922 (Box 47, Folder 507)
    - Gil, Enrique, 1939 October 26 (Box 47, Folder 508)
    - Granville-Baker, Harley, [1921?] (Box 47, Folder 509)
    - Gribble, Harry Wagstaff, 1938 December 25 (Box 47, Folder 510)
    - "H" General, 1914-1948 (Box 47, Folder 511-512)
    - Harcourt, Alfred, 1917-1921 (Box 47, Folder 513)
      Includes third party correspondence
    - Harper & Brothers, 1914-1915 (Box 47, Folder 514)
      Includes carbon of letter from Lewis and third party correspondence
    - Harriman, Margaret [Case?], [1947] June 2 (Box 47, Folder 515)
    - Hawthorne, Hildegarde, undated (Box 47, Folder 516)
    - Hayes, Helen, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 517)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1941 November 15 (Box 47, Folder 518)
    - Hergesheimer, Joseph, 1916-1922 (Box 47, Folder 519)
    - Hersey, John Richard, 1947 June 24 (Box 47, Folder 520)
    - Hervey, Harry, 1947 December 15 (Box 47, Folder 521)
    - Holbrook, Stewart [Hall?], 1947 June 13 (Box 47, Folder 522)
    - Howard, Sidney Coe, 1934 October 1 (Box 47, Folder 523)
    - Howells, William Dean, 1916 February 11 (Box 47, Folder 524)
    - Hoyt, Henry, [1917?] March 8 (Box 47, Folder 525)
    - Hughes, Rupert, 1914-1917 (Box 47, Folder 526)
    - Hurst, Fannie, undated (Box 47, Folder 527)
    - Hutchins, Robert Maynard, 1938 March 1 (Box 47, Folder 528)
    - "I" General, 1924 April 15 (Box 47, Folder 529)
    - India League of America, 1942 September 19 (Box 47, Folder 530)
    - International Rescue and Relief Committee, 1943 March 14 (Box 47, Folder 531)
    - "J" General, 1922-1947 (Box 47, Folder 532)
    - Johnson, Owen, 1915 October 18 (Box 47, Folder 533)
    - "K" General, 1915-1949 (Box 47, Folder 534)
    - Kelley, Marjorie, 1948 (Box 47, Folder 535)
    - Kenton, Edna, [1914?] (Box 47, Folder 536)
    - Kermott, Edward Plews, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 537)
      Includes genealogical information on Kermott family
    - Knights of Columbus, 1942 (Box 47, Folder 538)
    - Kraft, H. S. (Hyman Solomon), 1948, undated (Box 47, Folder 539)
    - "L" General, 1927-1947 (Box 47, Folder 540)
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1942 March 24 (Box 47, Folder 541)
    - Lawrence, Josephine, 1938 January 2 (Box 47, Folder 542)
    - Le Gallienne, Richard, [1914] (Box 47, Folder 543)
    - Leonard, William Ellery, 1922 October 22 (Box 47, Folder 544)
    - Lewis, Claude B. (brother), 1932-1950 (Box 47, Folder 545)
    - Lewis, Emeline (mother), n.y. November 15 (Box 47, Folder 546)
    - Lewis, Edwin J. (father), 1903-1922 (Box 47, Folder 547-550)
    - Lewis, Isabel Warner, 1903-1911 (Box 48, Folder 551)
    - Lewis, Wells (son), 1931-1935 (Box 48, Folder 552)
    - Lincoln, Victoria, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 553)
    - Lindsay, Vachel, 1920 December 15 (Box 48, Folder 554)
    - Lippmann, Walter, undated (Box 48, Folder 555)
    - London, Jack, 1910-1911 (Box 48, Folder 556)
    - Longwell, Daniel, 1932-1933 (Box 48, Folder 557)
    - Lorimer, George Horace, 1915-1919 (Box 48, Folder 558)
    - Lucke, Jerome B., 1914, 1921 (Box 48, Folder 559)
    - "M" General, 1915-1949 (Box 48, Folder 560)
    - Mackenzie, Compton, Sir, 1921-1922 (Box 48, Folder 561)
    - Macy, George, 1944 March 10 (Box 48, Folder 562)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1948 September 24 (Box 48, Folder 563)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1935 July 5 (Box 48, Folder 564)
    - Marquand, John P. (John Phillips), undated (Box 48, Folder 565)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1922, undated (Box 48, Folder 566)
    - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1920-1945 (Box 48, Folder 567)
      Includes "Satan Begone" by Carl Vogel
    - Mundy, Talbot, 1914 April 7 (Box 48, Folder 568)
    - Murdock, Victor, 1921 February 12 (Box 48, Folder 569)
    - "N" General, 1922-1949 (Box 48, Folder 570)
    - Nathan, George [Jean?], 1947 (Box 48, Folder 571)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1941 November 18 (Box 48, Folder 572)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1942 January 22 (Box 48, Folder 573)
    - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, 1942 February 4 (Box 48, Folder 574)
    - Nichols, Charles Washburn, 1920 December 31 (Box 48, Folder 575)
      Includes review of Main Street
    - Norris, Charles Gilman, 1920 November 16 (Box 48, Folder 576)
    - Norris, J. Frank, 1938 February 18 (Box 48, Folder 577)
    - "O" General, 1945-1947 (Box 48, Folder 578)
    - Oakley, Annie, undated (Box 48, Folder 579)
    - O'Connor, T. P. [(Thomas Power)?], 1922 (Box 48, Folder 580)
    - Odets, Clifford, 1935 December 31 (Box 48, Folder 581)
    - O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953, 1936 November 25 (Box 48, Folder 582)
    - O'Sheel, Shaemas, 1914 November 18 (Box 48, Folder 583)
    - "P" General, 1921-1947 (Box 48, Folder 584)
    - Palmer, Frederick, 1914 March 16 (Box 48, Folder 585)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1914-1920 (Box 48, Folder 586)
    - Poole, Ernest, 1915-1917 (Box 48, Folder 587)
    - Post War World Council, 1942 April 23 (Box 48, Folder 588)
    - Powers, Marcella, [1943?] (Box 48, Folder 589)
      Includes photograph
    - Prokosch, Frederic, 1944 February 3 (Box 48, Folder 590)
    - Quarles, Benjamin, 1947 May 22 (Box 48, Folder 591)
    - "R" General, 1927-1949 (Box 48, Folder 592)
    - Random House (Firm), 1943 (Box 48, Folder 593)
    - Raphaelson, Samson, 1943 May 11 (Box 48, Folder 594)
    - Rives, Amélie, [1914?] (Box 48, Folder 595)
    - Robeson, Eslanda Goode, 1947 June 17 (Box 48, Folder 596)
    - Rolland, Romain, 1935 (Box 48, Folder 597)
    - Rowolt Verlag, 1933-1946 (Box 48, Folder 598)
      Includes copy of letter from Lewis
    - Rutherford, Roy, 1945 April 16 (Box 48, Folder 599)
    - "S" General, 1917-1947 (Box 49, Folder 600)
    - Sadow, Morris, 1936-1948 (Box 49, Folder 601)
    - Salvemini, Gaetano, 1936 April 13 (Box 49, Folder 602)
    - Schuyler, George Samuel, 1948 June 17 (Box 49, Folder 603)
    - Scott, Evelyn, 1922 January 16 (Box 49, Folder 604)
    - Seldes, George, 1947 June 2 (Box 49, Folder 605)
    - Sinclair, May, 1922 (Box 49, Folder 606)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1915, 1921 (Box 49, Folder 607)
    - Smith, Thomas R., 1920 December 13 (Box 49, Folder 608)
    - Stassen, Harold Edward, 1942-1943 (Box 49, Folder 609)
    - Strange, Michael, undated (Box 49, Folder 610)
    - Sullivan, Mark, 1922 November 11 (Box 49, Folder 611)
    - "T" General, 1914-1949 (Box 49, Folder 612)
    - Targ, William, 1946 July 8 (Box 49, Folder 613)
    - Tarkington, Booth, 1921-1945 (Box 49, Folder 614)
    - Terhune, Albert Payson, 1915 September 27 (Box 49, Folder 615)
    - Thomas, Norman, 1947 June 9 (Box 49, Folder 616)
    - Thye, Edward J., 1943-1949 (Box 49, Folder 617)
    - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1920 (Box 49, Folder 618)
    - Toohey, John Peter, 1920 October 25 (Box 49, Folder 619)
    - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1914, 1920 (Box 49, Folder 620)
    - Tuttle, [Frank?], 1936 December 23 (Box 49, Folder 621)
      Includes photographs
    - "U" General, 1920-1948 (Box 49, Folder 622)
    - United China Relief, Inc., 1941 June 21 (Box 49, Folder 623)
    - United States. War Dept., 1944 November 9 (Box 49, Folder 624)
    - University of Minnesota, 1902 May 15 (Box 49, Folder 625)
    - Updegraff, Allan, [1914?] (Box 49, Folder 626)
    - "V" General, 1917-1947 (Box 49, Folder 627)
    - Vance, Arthur T. (Arthur Turner), 1920 December 14 (Box 49, Folder 628)
    - Vandenburg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1947 (Box 49, Folder 629)
    - Van Doren, Carl, 1920 November 22 (Box 49, Folder 630)
    - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1920 October 26 (Box 49, Folder 631)
    - "W" General, 1914-1947 (Box 49, Folder 632)
    - Wallace, Edgar, 1922 February 2 (Box 49, Folder 633)
    - Walpole, Hugh, Sir, 1920-1922 (Box 49, Folder 634)
    - Washburn, Claude, 1920-1921 (Box 49, Folder 635)
    - Watkins, Ann, 1928-1931 (Box 49, Folder 636-641)
      Includes letters from Lewis to Watkins and third party correspondence
    - Watkins, Ann, 1931-1948 (Box 50, Folder 642-643)
    - [Wayaspt?], Molly, 1945 (Box 50, Folder 644)
      Includes letters from Lewis
    - Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1922, 1935 (Box 50, Folder 645)
    - West, Rebecca, 1921-1948 (Box 50, Folder 646)
    - Wharton, Edith, 1921-1922 (Box 50, Folder 647)
    - Wiggin, Kate Douglas Smith, 1914 (Box 50, Folder 648)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1938, undated (Box 50, Folder 649)
    - Wood, Grant, 1937 July 10 (Box 50, Folder 650)
      Includes illustrations to Main Street
    - Woodward, William E., 1917 March 15 (Box 50, Folder 651)
    - Wright, Cuthbert, 1943 April 22 (Box 50, Folder 652)
    - "Y" General, 1915, 1938 (Box 50, Folder 653)
    - Yale University, 1936-1949 (Box 50, Folder 654)
    - "Z" General, undated (Box 50, Folder 655)
    - Zilkha, Berthie, 1945 January 15 (Box 50, Folder 656)
    - First Name Only, 1917-1949 (Box 50, Folder 657)
    - Unidentified, 1914-1948 (Box 50, Folder 658-659)
  - OUTGOING CORRESPONDENCE
    - Aiken, Charles S., 1910 August 20 (Box 51, Folder 660)
    - Aswell, Edward C. (Edward Campbell), 1938 (Box 51, Folder 661)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1909 (Box 51, Folder 662)
    - Berenson, Bernard, 1949 (Box 51, Folder 663)
    - Brush, Katharine, n.y. February 7 (Box 51, Folder 664)
    - Conlin, Katherine, 1931 March 28 (Box 51, Folder 665)
    - Doubleday, Doran & Co., 1932-1940 (Box 51, Folder 666)
    - Edgett, Edwin Francis, 1915 June 28 (Box 51, Folder 667)
    - Foerster, Norman, 1921-1944 (Box 51, Folder 668)
    - Freeburg, Victor O., 1908-1937 (Box 51, Folder 669)
    - Gallup, Donald, 1948-1949 (Box 51, Folder 670)
    - Garland, Hamlin, 1915 September 23 (Box 51, Folder 671)
    - Hazlitt, Henry, 1931-1944 (Box 51, Folder 672)
    - William Heinemann Publishers, 1929-1950 (Box 51, Folder 673)
    - Howard, Sidney, 1937, undated (Box 51, Folder 674)
    - Huebsch, B.W., 1928-1945 (Box 51, Folder 675)
    - Jordan, Elizabeth, 1915-1938 (Box 51, Folder 676)
    - Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1939-1940 (Box 51, Folder 677)
    - Leonard, George, 1944 October 25 (Box 51, Folder 678)
    - Lewis, Claude B. (brother), 1925 (Box 51, Folder 679)
    - Lewis, Edwin J. (father), 1904-1926 (Box 51, Folder 680-689)
      Includes photographs of Wells and Grace Hegger Lewis
    - Maxwell, Perrinton, 1930 November 15 (Box 51, Folder 690)
    - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1933 June 4 (Box 51, Folder 691)
    - Mitchell, Sigrid, 1946 December 25 (Box 51, Folder 692)
    - Moseley, ----, 1926 December 12 (Box 51, Folder 693)
    - The Nation, 1931 August 20 (Box 51, Folder 694-695)
    - O'Donnell, 1931 August 6 (Box 52, Folder 696)
    - Phillips, Henry Albert, 1929 November 22 (Box 52, Folder 697)
    - Prescott, Joseph, 1934 January 12 (Box 52, Folder 698)
    - Raphaelson, Samuel, 1929-1946 (Box 52, Folder 699)
    - Russell, James A., 1948 April 18 (Box 52, Folder 700)
    - Saunders, ----, 1921 February 16 (Box 52, Folder 701)
    - Sillcox, Luise, 1948 May 8 (Box 52, Folder 702)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1928 January 3 (Box 52, Folder 703)
    - Smith, Harry B., 1919-1920 (Box 52, Folder 704)
    - Sterling, George, 1921 (Box 52, Folder 705)
    - Troxell, Gilbert, 1937-1946 (Box 52, Folder 706)
      Includes photograph of Lewis
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1925 August 26 (Box 52, Folder 707)
    - Viereck, George Silvester, 1931 June 27 (Box 52, Folder 708)
    - Warren, Dale, 1935-1941 (Box 52, Folder 709)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1935 June 17 (Box 52, Folder 710)
    - Williamstown (Mass.), 1948 March 31 (Box 52, Folder 711)
    - Wright, H. W., 1913 April 5 (Box 52, Folder 712)
    - Yale University Library, 1938-1949 (Box 52, Folder 713)
    - Young, Gordon Ray, 1915-1918 (Box 52, Folder 714)
    - First Name Only, [1927] June 17 (Box 52, Folder 715)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Curtis Brown, Ltd. to Ernst, Cane, Berner & Gitlin, 1952 February 25 (Box 52, Folder 716)
      Includes copies of letters from Lewis to Frances Benn Hall dating from 1940 to 1947
    - Ernst, Cane, Berner, & Gitlin to Yale University Library, 1964 January 20 (Box 52, Folder 717)
    - Hall, France Benn to Ernst, Cane, Berner & Gitlin, 1952 February 22 (Box 52, Folder 718)
    - Heffelfinger, Frank to Norman Holmes Pearson, 1951 March 29 (Box 52, Folder 719)
    - Lewis, Grace Hegger to [Wells Lewis?], n.y. August 30 (Box 52, Folder 720)
    - McCurdy, J. A. Douglas to Stokes & Company, 1912 August 12 (Box 52, Folder 721)
    - Yale University Library to Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1951 March 29 (Box 52, Folder 722)
    - Unidentified to Norman Pearson, 1951 March 13 (Box 52, Folder 723)
    - Copies of Letters, [1866?] (Box 52, Folder 724)
- Photographs, 1888-1950; Series III; 1.67 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Series III, Photographs, housed in boxes 53-56, is organized into six subseries: Photographs of Sinclair Lewis, Studio and Artists' Portraits of Sinclair Lewis, Family and Others, Photographs of Plays, Places, and Other. Photographs of Sinclair Lewis are subdivided for portraits and snaphots and photographs of Lewis with others and arranged chronologically within each subdivision. Photographs in other subseries are arranged alphabetically.
  The series features photographs of Lewis in snapshots, studio and other portraits, and stage scenes from plays and theatrical adaptations of novels. Photographs include family scenes from early childhood (1894) to a portrait in Florence, Italy shortly before his death (1950). Studio and artists' portraits include photographs by Robert H. Davis, Trude Fleischmann, Eric Schaal, and Carl Van Vechten.
  There are also photographs of Grace MacKowan Cooke, Irving Fisher, Grace Hegger Lewis, Marcella Powers, Albert Payson Terhune, Dorothy Thompson, and members of the Lewis and Kermott families.
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF SINCLAIR LEWIS
    - Portraits and snapshots, 1888-1950, undated (Box 53, Folder 725-726)
    - Photographs of Sinclair Lewis with others, 1894-1947, undated (Box 53, Folder 727-745)
      Includes photographs of William Rose Benét, George Sterling, Albert Payson Terhune, Dorothy Thompson, Henry Travers, Marcella Powers, and unidentified others
    - Photograph albums, 1916, undated (Box 53, Folder 746)
  - STUDIO AND ARTISTS' PORTRAITS OF SINCLAIR LEWIS
    - Davis, Robert H., undated (Box 53, Folder 747)
    - Figaro, Charles, [1916?] (Box 53, Folder 748)
    - Fleischmann, Trude, undated (Box 53, Folder 749)
    - Grant, Franklin, undated (Box 53, Folder 750)
    - Haussler, ----, undated (Box 53, Folder 751)
    - Ray Huff Studios, 1940 May (Box 53, Folder 752)
    - Lindsey, Frank, 1931 (Box 53, Folder 753)
    - Pach Brothers, undated (Box 53, Folder 754-756)
    - Pinchot,----, undated (Box 54, Folder 757)
    - Pugh, Mabel, undated (Box 54, Folder 758)
    - Schaal, Eric, undated (Box 54, Folder 759)
    - Stein, Harold, undated (Box 54, Folder 760)
    - Talbot, ----, undated (Box 54, Folder 761)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1938 January 5 (Box 54, Folder 762-763)
    - Whitesell, undated
    - [Empty folder], undated (Box 54, Folder 764)
  - FAMILY AND OTHERS
    - Family
      - Kermott, Edward (grandfather), undated (Box 54, Folder 765)
      - Kermott, Mrs. Edward, undated (Box 54, Folder 766)
      - Kermott, "Lou", undated (Box 54, Folder 767)
      - Kermott, Nellie, undated (Box 54, Folder 768)
      - [Lewis], Claude B. (brother), undated (Box 54, Folder 769)
      - Lewis, Edwin J. (father), undated (Box 54, Folder 770)
      - Lewis, Emma Kermott (mother), undated (Box 54, Folder 771)
      - Lewis, Freeman, 1911, undated (Box 54, Folder 772)
      - Lewis, Grace Hegger (wife), undated (Box 54, Folder 773)
      - Lewis, Grace Hegger and Wells Lewis, undated (Box 54, Folder 774)
      - Lewis, Michael (son), undated (Box 54, Folder 775)
      - Lewis, Wells (son), undated (Box 54, Folder 776)
      - Plews, ----, undated (Box 54, Folder 777)
      - Thomas, Calvin, undated (Box 54, Folder 778)